<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Case of the glass-makers in and about the city of London</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1699</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A31160</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1081</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T191267</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">08882448</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 08882448</idno>
            <idno type="VID">41988</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A31160)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 41988)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1279:8 or 21242:118)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Case of the glass-makers in and about the city of London</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproductions of originals in the Goldsmiths' Library, University of London and the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Glass manufacture --  England --  London.</term>
               <term>Tariff --  Great Britain.</term>
               <term>Coal trade --  Great Britain.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:41988:1"/>
            <head>The CASE of the <hi>Glaſs-makers</hi> in and about the City of <hi>London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p n="1">I. THE <hi>Glaſs</hi> Manufacture is very beneficial and advantagious to this Nation, and might be much more improv'd, if ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficiently encourag'd, and much greater Quantities exported, if Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reigners were not enabled to underſell us in Foreign Markets; which they can do, not only from the high Duties on <hi>Salt Petre, Berilla, Foreign Aſhes,</hi> and other Materials uſed in the ſaid Manufacture,<note place="margin">
                  <hi>N.B.</hi> Saltpetre is double the Value in <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> to what it is in <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi>
               </note> but from the Difference between the Duties on our own <hi>Coals</hi> brought <hi>Coaſtwiſe,</hi> particularly into the <hi>Port of London,</hi> and on thoſe exported <hi>abroad.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The ſeveral Duties on <hi>Coals</hi> ſpent at <hi>London,</hi> amount to <hi>per Chaldron</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>9</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Duty on <hi>Coals</hi> exported, (if laid on <hi>London Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure</hi>) is but <hi>per Chaldr.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>3</cell>
                     <cell>0</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Difference in favour of <hi>Foreigners,</hi> is <hi>per Caldr.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>Which conſidering the great Quantity of Coals ſpent in the working of a ſmall Quantity of Glaſs, makes a very great Difference in the Value of it when wrought.</p>
            <p n="2">II. Beſides the Advantage given to <hi>Foreigners,</hi> by furniſhing them with Materials for underworking us at cheaper Prices than to our Natives; the Duties on Exportation of <hi>Britiſh</hi> Glaſs is a great Hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drance to its being exported abroad, whilſt the <hi>French King,</hi> for the enabling his Subjects to afford their Glaſs cheap, gives to the Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facturers thereof their Fewel <hi>gratis.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">III. As there are continually new Manufactures of <hi>Glaſs</hi> ſetting up in the Northern Parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> particularly <hi>Muſcovy, Hamburgh, Pruſſia,</hi> &amp;c. it is neceſſary alſo to regulate the Duties on <hi>Foreign Glaſs imported,</hi> ſo as that Foreigners may not be enabled to underſell us <hi>at home</hi> as well as <hi>abroad,</hi> which would be the total Ruin of the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufacture.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. The Duties now laid on the <hi>Importation</hi> of Foreign Glaſs are ſome of them <hi>too low,</hi> particularly thoſe on <hi>Normandy</hi> or <hi>Crown Glaſs,</hi> which as the Duties now ſtand would in Time of Peace be imported cheaper from <hi>France</hi> than our <hi>own Crown Glaſs</hi> can be afforded at; and others of them, particularly all Looking-glaſs Plates of above 12 Inches in Length (which was the largeſt Size known when the <hi>Act of Tonnage and Poundage</hi> paſſed) pay Duties <hi>ad valorem,</hi> which is to be proved by the <hi>Oaths of the Importers;</hi> and there are but too many inſtances to prove, that ſuch <hi>Oaths</hi> are little regarded, whereby the Intent of the Duties will be loſt. Whereas were the low Duties advanc'd, and the Duties now laid <hi>ad Valorem</hi> put upon the <hi>Meaſure and Size,</hi> ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to which the Value of Glaſs Plates is ſettled, the ſame would effectually prevent any Colluſion or Avoidance of the Duties.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Glaſs-makers therefore humbly pray the Honourable Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons to give them ſuch Relief in the Duties abovementioned, as they ſhall think moſt proper for the Encouragement of ſo uſeful a Manufacture.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:41988:2"/>
            <p>THE CASE OF THE <hi>Glaſs-makers,</hi> Relating to the Duties on COALS, and on GLASS Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported and Imported.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
